Kye Smith

https://kyesmith.me kye@kyesmith.me Professional developer with a thirst to adapt, learn and succeed. A self-driven, charismatic team player with a genuine interest in software & technology. Happiest when learning or being challenged on current knowledge. Also a keen photographer, guitarist and rubiks cube solver.

Development Experience

Wren Kitchens, Junior Javascript Developer (August 2019 - Present)

My time at Wren has been spent working on their bespoke kitchen planning software. This is a large, CAD-like, data-driven Typescript project which is used by every Wren kitchen designer in the country. I started as a graduate developer and was promoted to a junior position after 3 months of training. Since then, I have worked on multiple teams across almost all areas of the project; handling both bug fixes and the addition of new features. This has meant working on everything from data management to their three-dimensional engine to UI updates. Outside of actually writing code, I often take an active part in meetings with business analysts, project managers and members of the QA team; advising on the amount of work changes/fixes may require and raising concerns with business requests where necessary. I also often help my fellow junior developers and even higher level colleagues with their own issues. After the recent lockdown, I was among one of two junior developers picked to be brought back into the office 6 weeks before the rest of the team to get development back on track.

Skills

- Professional experience in Javascript/Typescript and with the following associated technologies; NodeJS/NPM,
 React, Redux, Webpack, HTML5 heavily including canvas, CSS/LESS, InversifyJS, JQuery, Git.
- Professional experience using RESTful APIs.
- Professional experience working in an Agile team following SCRUM methodologies (both in sprints and kanban),
 with the aid of Jira, Bitbucket and Confluence.
- Additionally, experience in VueJS and a working understanding when it comes to C# and SQL.

Education

The University of Sheffield (September 2014 – June 2019)

BEng: Electronic Engineering.

Wyke Sixth Form College (September 2012 – June 2014)

A-levels: Physics - B, Mathematics - B, Chemistry - B, Biology - C. Additionally, AS-level Accounting - A.

Hull Trinity House School (September 2007 – June 2012)

GCSEs: Physics - A*, Mathematics - A, Chemistry - A, Biology - A, English Literature - B, ENglish Language - B, Geography - C.

Previous Experience

The University of Sheffield, Residence Life Mentor (September 2018 – June 2019)

Offering guidance and support to students living in the halls of residence; an approachable and friendly face for other students.

The Mission Public House, Assistant Manager (June 2017 – September 2018)

Responsible for day-to-day running, including leading a team of 10 or more, stock management and completing takings paperwork.